So now we can get into after later and before we can't use it from now.
所以现在我们可以在以后和之前进入，从现在开始我们就不能使用它了。
So let's just cross that out.
所以让我们把它划掉。
We're not going to use that after it later and before can be used to talk about a time that happened
我们不会在之后使用它，之前可以用来谈论发生的时间
after or before a point that's in the future or the past future or past.
在未来或过去未来或过去的某个点之后或之前。
So here's the point.
所以这就是重点。
Here's the point.
这就是重点。
And we're going to talk about something that happened over here or something that happened over here
我们将谈论这里发生的事情或这里发生的事情
or something that happened over here.
或者这里发生的事情。
Something that happened over here.
这里发生了一些事情。
Not now.
现在不要。
We're not going to focus on now.
我们现在不打算关注。
OK so let's say future or past future or past point It works basically the same way as in an ago except
好的，让我们说未来或过去未来或过去点它的工作方式与以前基本相同，除了
now point is moved into the future or moved into the past and we don't talk about now some examples.
现在点是移到未来还是移到过去，我们现在不谈论一些例子。
OK.
好的。
Let's go simple at first.
让我们先简单一点。
A week before my vacation next June I need to get my visa if I wanted to be very specific about the
明年六月假期前一周，如果我想非常具体地了解我需要获得签证
time I could say in six months I'm going on vacation.
六个月后我可以说我要去度假了。
OK.
好的。
A week before my vacation which is in six months which is next June whatever I need to get my visa.
我假期前一周，也就是六个月后，也就是明年六月，无论我需要什么签证。
So this is June.
所以这是六月。
In the future.
在将来。
OK.
好的。
And this is a week before that.
这是在那之前的一周。
One week before.
一周前。
Here's now.
现在到了。
We don't worry about that.
我们不担心这个。
A week before that.
在那之前的一周。
I need to get my visa which is what we need to travel.
我需要得到我的签证，这是我们旅行所需要的。
Obviously when we travel we need a visa.
显然，当我们旅行时，我们需要签证。
OK.
好的。
So that makes sense.
所以这是有道理的。
We could say there's another pass point.
我们可以说还有另一个通过点。
Let's say this is my 11th birthday bidet.
假设这是我 11 岁生日的坐浴盆。
We often write bidet.
我们经常写坐浴盆。
OK.
好的。
Three months after my 11th birthday.
在我 11 岁生日后三个月。
Well it's not my 11th birthday now.
好吧，现在不是我的 11 岁生日。
So my 11th birthday was over 70 years ago three months after my 11th birthday.
所以我的 11 岁生日是在我 11 岁生日三个月后的 70 多年前。
I broke my leg three months after my 11th birthday I broke my leg three months before my 11th birthday.
我在 11 岁生日后三个月摔断了腿 我在 11 岁生日前三个月摔断了腿。
Three months before my 11th birthday I moved to a new city.
在我 11 岁生日前三个月，我搬到了一个新城市。
I moved to a new city with my family.
我和家人搬到了一个新城市。
OK.
好的。
But again it's from this point from this point or I could say I turned eleven on June 14th six months
但同样是从这一点开始，或者我可以说我在 6 月 14 日满 11 岁了六个月
later something happened.
后来发生了一些事情。
OK.
好的。
Pretty simple.
很简单。
I had moved to a new city a month before.
一个月前我搬到了一个新城市。
So that's how we can use before.
所以这就是我们之前可以使用的方式。
Before what.
在什么之前。
Well before I turned eleven a month before I turned eleven which was on June 14th for example.
早在我满 11 岁之前的一个月，例如 6 月 14 日。
OK.
好的。
A few more examples.
再举几个例子。
After after getting married I became more responsible.
结婚后，我变得更加负责。
Now that one's not connected to a specific date but I was married in the past and then after that time
现在一个人与特定日期没有联系，但我过去结婚了，然后在那之后
probably until now.
大概到现在。
Maybe maybe not after that time I changed so we can use this way to express it.
也许不是在那次之后我改变了，所以我们可以用这种方式来表达它。
So the point there is we can use events instead of dates.
所以关键是我们可以使用事件而不是日期。
For example in the future after I move to New York City NYC they also call that the Big Apple.
例如，将来我搬到纽约市纽约市后，他们也称其为大苹果公司。
After I moved to New York City I plan to start small business.
搬到纽约市后，我计划开始做小生意。
So this one is not about when it happens exactly but there's a thing that's going to happen in the future
所以这不是关于它何时发生，而是未来会发生一件事
not now and then another thing that will happen after that you could say something that will happen
不是偶尔会发生的另一件事，然后你可以说会发生的事情
before that we don't need to say the dates.
在此之前我们不需要说e 日期。
We don't need to say exactly when we're just trying to relate events in time.
我们不需要准确地说出我们何时只是试图及时关联事件。
Basically I arrived in Beijing in 2012 a year later.
基本上我是在一年后的 2012 年到达北京的。
I met my wife a year later.
一年后我认识了我的妻子。
I met my wife.
我遇见了我的妻子。
OK so this is when it happened.
好的，这就是它发生的时候。
Could I use for example before here.
我可以在这里之前使用例如吗？
Well yeah.
嗯，是的。
Could say a year before I met my wife.
可以说是在我遇到我妻子的前一年。
I moved to Beijing.
我搬到了北京。
Basically it's the same idea the same idea.
基本上它是相同的想法相同的想法。
If you're hungry before 5 p.m. You'll have to cook by yourself before we have to cook by yourself.
如果你在下午 5 点之前饿了。在我们必须自己做饭之前，您必须自己做饭。
So OK.
那么好吧。
Maybe a mother is talking to her son.
也许一位母亲正在和她的儿子说话。
Usually she cooks for her son.
通常她为她的儿子做饭。
Today she can't.
今天她不能。
Maybe she's very busy.
也许她很忙。
If you feel hungry this is in the future.
如果你觉得饿了，那就是未来。
Maybe now it's 2 p.m..
也许现在是下午 2 点。
Son if you feel hungry before 5 you'll have to cook for yourself.
儿子，如果您在 5 点之前感到饥饿，您将不得不自己做饭。
OK so so that means if it's after she will cook for him.
好的，这意味着如果在她为他做饭之后。
If this is 5 p.m. after it OK she will cook for him before she cannot she cannot.
如果这是下午 5 点。没事之后，她会在她不能之前为他做饭，她不能。
She will be busy so he will have to cook for himself before that.
她会很忙，所以在那之前他得自己做饭。
This is in the future.
这是在未来。
One more thing very quickly.
另一件事很快。
I have so much to prepare before my exam.
考试前我有很多准备。
I'm really stressed out I'm stressed out out and out OK.
我真的很紧张，我很紧张。
So hopefully that's clear now.
所以希望现在很清楚。
When we use in when we use a go when we use after later and before.
当我们使用时在我们使用时我们使用之后和之前。
I hope it's very clear.
我希望它很清楚。